<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Static mirror hosting on Icarus Project</title>
    <link>/docs/static-mirroring/static-hosting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Static mirror hosting on Icarus Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>info@fightcensorship.tech (Icarus Project)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>info@fightcensorship.tech (Icarus Project)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Some rights reserved. Unless otherwise noted, content on this page is under a Creative Commons license.</copyright><atom:link href="/docs/static-mirroring/static-hosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hosting on Amazon S3</title>
      <link>/docs/static-mirroring/static-hosting/amazons3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>info@fightcensorship.tech (Icarus Project)</author>
      <guid>/docs/static-mirroring/static-hosting/amazons3/</guid>
      <description>Required expertise level : Intermediate
Platform : Any
Last tested and confirmed : January 2022
Amazon S3 (Amazon Simple Storage Service) is a data storage service and one of the Amazon Web Services (AWS)
S3 provides object storage service, which means that data is stored and addressed as objects, each object contains it&amp;rsquo;s own data in addition to meta-data and a unique identifier.
Object storage is often used to store big amounts of data that doesn&amp;rsquo;t need the features and structure of the file systems hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting on Google Cloud Storage</title>
      <link>/docs/static-mirroring/static-hosting/gcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>info@fightcensorship.tech (Icarus Project)</author>
      <guid>/docs/static-mirroring/static-hosting/gcs/</guid>
      <description>Required expertise level : Intermediate
Platform : Any
Last tested and confirmed : January 2022
Google Cloud Storage is object storage service similar to Amazon S3, and it provides the ability to serve static web pages as well.
The main advantage of using Google Cloud Storage to host our static mirror is the ability to serve a fully functional &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo; web pages directly using Google Cloud Platform URLs which usually looks like this: https://storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting on GitHub</title>
      <link>/docs/static-mirroring/static-hosting/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>info@fightcensorship.tech (Icarus Project)</author>
      <guid>/docs/static-mirroring/static-hosting/github/</guid>
      <description>Required expertise level : Intermediate
Platform : Any
Last tested and confirmed : January 2022
GitHub is a software development platform using Git version control system, and it provides the ability to serve static web pages through GitHub Pages service.
Note GitHub provides an easy step-by-step guide on how to host a static website on their platform. The guide is available in English, so, in order to avoid redundancy we&amp;rsquo;ll just refer to it here and add a translated version for every available language in our documentations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
