<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Icarus Project – Icarus Project Blog</title><link>/blog.html</link><description>Recent content in Icarus Project Blog on Icarus Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Introducing Icarus Project</title><link>/blog/2020/09/19/introducing-icarus-project.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/09/19/introducing-icarus-project.html</guid><description>
&lt;div class="card rounded p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4" style="max-width: 610px">
&lt;img class="card-img-top" src="../blog/2020/09/19/introducing-icarus-project/logo_hubd07df05cf1faee0af1a1547178b69a4_20304_600x300_fill_catmullrom_smart1_2.png" width="600" height="300">
&lt;div class="card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0">
&lt;p class="card-text">
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
With the &lt;strong>first release&lt;/strong> of Icarus Project&amp;rsquo;s documentations, we are happy to announce the results of our research and documentation process.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The project idea&lt;/strong> started as an individual initiative in 2017, trying to collect, test, document, and develop Internet censorship circumvention techniques as a response to the rise of Internet censorship at the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In 2019&lt;/strong> the idea started to be realized through one year fellowship program supported by Open Tech Fund (OTF) Information Controls Fellowship program, and hosted by &lt;a href="https://www.stratosphereips.org/team">Stratosphere Lab&lt;/a> at the Czech Technical University in Prague (CVUT).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We started by collecting, testing, and documenting as many ideas and methods as we can.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Now,&lt;/strong> we present these guides and documentations to serve as the core of this project. We are hoping that this initial release should it prove - useful and effective - will receive and integrate different contributions from the interested communities, towards developing and maintaining an accessible and user-friendly online repository of accumulative experience and research.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Feel free to reach out and let us know what do you think and how can we improve, &lt;a href="../community">checkout the community page&lt;/a>, also, checkout the &lt;a href="../docs/contribution-guidelines/">Contribution Guidelines&lt;/a> if you are interested!
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>